<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Elections on Civic Innovation Competition</title>
    <link>/tags/elections/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Elections on Civic Innovation Competition</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/elections/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Election Field Techs</title>
      <link>/project/ps-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/ps-3/</guid>
      <description>Summary of problem: We utilize up to 20 field technicians on election day, whose duties vary between voting machine repair, to resupply support, to other election procedure assistance. Some are based in the office and deployed by a supervisor to an area of need. Others have a “territory” in which they operate. Currently, we are not able to track these technicians to most efficiently deploy them.
How it affects the organization: Most significant impact is that we are not able to most effectively optimize the deployment of our field technicians on Election Day.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Voter Wait Times</title>
      <link>/project/ps-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/ps-2/</guid>
      <description>Summary of problem: We currently rely on a manual process of calling sites for their best estimations of wait-times which is time consuming and not accurate. Currently this information is also not reported back out to the public in real-time.
How it affects the organization: The manual collection of this information is time consuming and mostly inaccurate. This decreases real-time flexibility in resource allocation, hinders our ability to identify problems quickly and makes it difficult to respond to media inquiries at times.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>