<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Civic Innovation Competition on Civic Innovation Competition</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Civic Innovation Competition on Civic Innovation Competition</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 15 Oct 2017 00:00:00 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Privacy Policy</title>
      <link>/privacy/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Jun 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/privacy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Understanding Local Government</title>
      <link>/project/ps-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/ps-1/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;summary-of-problem&#34;&gt;Summary of problem:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When attempting to understand programs, services and even taxes it can be incredibly difficult to delineate between Guilford County and the municipalities that are contained within. Citizens generally have a difficult time understanding who to contact and in some cases may feel hindered or discouraged by this lack of understanding. We do a good job of providing information on our website but citizens would need to know what they are looking for to access it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-it-affects-the-organization&#34;&gt;How it affects the organization:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;People in all local government organizations are regularly contacted by citizens asking questions unrelated to their area of focus or their organization. Although a majority of the time we do a good job of directing people, this can create difficult and sometimes frustrating interactions with the public. We may also be missing opportunities to serve people because they are turned away by their lack of understanding or frustration.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;current-state-of-problem&#34;&gt;Current state of problem:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are in the process of redesigning our website to be more user friendly but that doesn’t completely solve the problem. Our website is only a piece of the local government puzzle in Guilford County and determining a proper point-of-entry is still up to the end user.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;ideal-state-and-its-benefits&#34;&gt;Ideal state and its benefits:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An ideal state could possibly be one where citizen personas have been crafted to help direct people to information regardless of the organization providing it. The citizen has an opportunity to say what they are interested in so they can then be seamlessly directed.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Voter Wait Times</title>
      <link>/project/ps-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/ps-2/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;summary-of-problem&#34;&gt;Summary of problem:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We currently rely on a manual process of calling sites for their best estimations of wait-times which is time consuming and not accurate. Currently this information is also not reported back out to the public in real-time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-it-affects-the-organization&#34;&gt;How it affects the organization:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The manual collection of this information is time consuming and mostly inaccurate. This decreases real-time flexibility in resource allocation, hinders our ability to identify problems quickly and makes it difficult to respond to media inquiries at times.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;current-state-of-problem&#34;&gt;Current state of problem:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Currently, wait-times are collected manually via phone calls and rely on visual approximations. These wait-times are currently not reported back out to the public in real time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;ideal-state-and-its-benefits&#34;&gt;Ideal state and its benefits:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Voters would be able to see wait-times on our website in real time. This could be utilized by voters, especially during early voting, to plan appropriately and utilize previously underutilized voting sites.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Person Re-Identification System For Mobile Devices</title>
      <link>/publication/person-re-identification/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2015 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/person-re-identification/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;More detail can easily be written here using &lt;em&gt;Markdown&lt;/em&gt; and $\rm \LaTeX$ math code.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mobile visual clothing search</title>
      <link>/publication/clothing-search/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2013 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/clothing-search/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;More detail can easily be written here using &lt;em&gt;Markdown&lt;/em&gt; and $\rm \LaTeX$ math code.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Application</title>
      <link>/post/application/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/application/</guid>
      <description>&lt;script src=&#34;https://myguilford.seamlessdocs.com/s/da65f3146615a13a9d684c34b46cf687/embed/iframe&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
